let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the act of joining the slip gauges together for building up sizes?",
    immg: "img1",
    answer: "Wringing",
    options: ["Glazing", "Pinning", "Loading", "Wringing"]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which material is used for manufacturing sine bar?",
    immg: "img2",
    answer: "Stabilized chromium steel",
    options: ["Invar steel", "High speed steel", "High carbon steel", "Stabilized chromium steel"]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What is the specification of sine bar?",
    immg: "img3",
    answer: "Distance between centre points of the rollers",
    options: [
      "Distance between outer points of the rollers",
      "Distance between inner points of the rollers",
      "Distance between centre points of the rollers",
      "Distance between the edges of the sine bar"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which one forms the hypotenuse of the triangle while checking with sine bar?",
    immg: "img4",
    answer: "Sine bar length",
    options: [
      "Surface plate",
      "Sine bar width",
      "Sine bar length",
      "Slip gauges height"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What is the name of the instrument that measures surface quality shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img5",
    answer: "Mechanical surface indicator",
    options: [
      "Dial test indicator",
      "Electrical surface indicator",
      "Electronic surface indicator",
      "Mechanical surface indicator"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Why manual stroking is preferred for large quantities in honing operation?",
    immg: "img6",
    answer: "To keep close tolerance",
    options: [
      "To reduce cost",
      "To reduce time",
      "To keep close tolerance",
      "To reduce maintenance cost"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which grade slip gauge is used for precision tool room applications?",
    immg: "img7",
    answer: "Grade I",
    options: ["Grade 00", "Grade 0", "Grade I", "Grade II"]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which material is used to make slip gauge block?",
    immg: "img8",
    answer: "High grade steel",
    options: ["Tool steel", "Low grade steel", "High grade steel", "High carbon steel"]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which finishing operation is performed by the tool that rotates and reciprocates simultaneously?",
    immg: "img9",
    answer: "Honing",
    options: ["Drilling", "Honing", "Lapping", "Grinding"]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which precision finishing operation carried out using fine abrasive materials?",
    immg: "img10",
    answer: "Lapping",
    options: ["Filing", "Grinding", "Reaming", "Lapping"]
  },
    {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which surface is being lapped using the split bush shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img11",
    answer: "External cylindrical surface",
    options: [
      "External cylindrical surface",
      "Flate surface",
      "Internal cylindrical surface",
      "External taper surface"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as ‘X’ shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img12",
    answer: "Length of sine bar",
    options: [
      "Length of sine bar",
      "Drilled holes",
      "Contact rollers",
      "Width"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as ‘X’ shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img13",
    answer: "Height of slip gauge",
    options: [
      "Height of slip gauge",
      "Length of sine bar",
      "Datum surface",
      "Taper angle"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "What is the height of slip gauge (q = 25° = 0.4226)?",
    immg: "img14",
    answer: "42.26",
    options: ["41.26", "42.26", "43.26", "44.26"]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which grade of slip gauge is used for inspection?",
    immg: "img15",
    answer: "Grade ‘0’ accuracy",
    options: [
      "Grade I accuracy",
      "Grade ‘0’ accuracy",
      "Grade ‘00’ accuracy",
      "Grade II accuracy"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which process is carried out with abrasive sticks to correct the profile of internal cylindrical surfaces?",
    immg: "img16",
    answer: "Honing",
    options: ["Lapping", "Honing", "Grinding", "Filing"]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which is the hardest of all abrasive materials?",
    immg: "img17",
    answer: "Diamond",
    options: [
      "Silicon carbide",
      "Boron carbide",
      "Diamond",
      "Aluminium oxide"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What is the name of the instrument shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img18",
    answer: "Height gauge with slip gauge holder",
    options: [
      "Depth vernier gauge",
      "Vernier height gauge",
      "Clamp type height gauge",
      "Height gauge with slip gauge holder"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which grade of slip gauge is used in general workshop?",
    immg: "img19",
    answer: "Grade II accuracy",
    options: [
      "Grade I accuracy",
      "Grade II accuracy",
      "Grade ‘0’ accuracy",
      "Grade ‘00’ accuracy"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "What is the name of the slip gauge grade used for inspection?",
    immg: "img20",
    answer: "Grade '0'",
    options: ["Grade I", "Grade '0'", "Grade '00'", "Grade II"]
  },
  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as 'x' shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img21",
    answer: "Protector slip",
    options: ["Chamois leather", "Leather pad", "Protector slip", "Steel sheet"]
  },
  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "What is the use of grade '00' accuracy slip gauges?",
    immg: "img22",
    answer: "Calibration grade",
    options: [
      "Inspection grade",
      "Tool room applications",
      "General workshop applications",
      "Calibration grade"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Which term refers to the operation of joining the slip gauges together for building up sizes?",
    immg: "img23",
    answer: "Wringing",
    options: ["Honing", "Lapping", "Wringing", "Polishing"]
  },
  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "What is the advantage of using a pair of special jaws in slip gauge holder?",
    immg: "img24",
    answer: "To measure the external & internal dimensions",
    options: [
      "To measure the external & internal dimensions",
      "To measure the height",
      "To measure the steps",
      "To measure the angular dimensions"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "What is the name of the application of slip gauge shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img25",
    answer: "Checking center distance of holes",
    options: [
      "Drawing circles",
      "Checking height",
      "Checking center distance of holes",
      "Layout work"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "What is the purpose of drilled holes in sine bar?",
    immg: "img26",
    answer: "To reduce the weight",
    options: [
      "Clamping of dial test indicator",
      "Clamping of slip gauges",
      "To reduce the weight",
      "For aesthetic purposes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "What is the use of Taly - Surf?",
    immg: "img27",
    answer: "To measure surface texture",
    options: [
      "To measure angle",
      "To measure flatness",
      "To measure parallelism",
      "To measure surface texture"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "Which is called as super finishing process?",
    immg: "img28",
    answer: "Honing",
    options: ["Turning", "Milling", "Grinding", "Honing"]
  },
  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "What is the name of the operation that corrects the profiles of cylindrical surfaces and removes taper?",
    immg: "img29",
    answer: "Honing",
    options: ["Boring", "Honing", "Grinding", "Reaming"]
  },
  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as 'x' shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img30",
    answer: "Bronze guide",
    options: ["Stone", "Bronze guide", "Universal joint", "Expanding body"]
  },
  {
    numb: 31,
    question: "What is the use of frosting operation?",
    immg: "img31",
    answer: "To increase the oil retention on scraped surfaces",
    options: [
      "To decrease the oil retention on scraped surfaces",
      "To increase the oil retention on milled surfaces",
      "To increase the oil retention on scraped surfaces",
      "To decrease the oil retention on milled surfaces"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 32,
    question: "Which method of surface hardening is shown in the figure?",
    immg: "img32",
    answer: "Pack-carburising",
    options: [
      "Nitriding",
      "Pack-carburising",
      "Flame hardening",
      "Induction hardening"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 33,
    question: "Which process refines the structure of steel component?",
    immg: "img33",
    answer: "Normalising",
    options: ["Tempering", "Annealing", "Hardening", "Normalising"]
  },
  {
    numb: 34,
    question: "Which method of surface hardening is done in a heated salt bath?",
    immg: "img34",
    answer: "Liquid carburising",
    options: [
      "Flame hardening",
      "Gas carburising",
      "Pack carburising",
      "Liquid carburising"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 35,
    question: "Which heat treatment process improves the machinability and ductility of the material?",
    immg: "img35",
    answer: "Annealing",
    options: ["Annealing", "Hardening", "Tempering", "Normalizing"]
  },
  {
    numb: 36,
    question: "Which metallic coating is done by rolling the layers of metal on to base metal?",
    immg: "img36",
    answer: "Cladding",
    options: ["Spraying", "Cladding", "Enamelling", "Molten metal bath"]
  },
  {
    numb: 37,
    question: "Which type of key is screwed on to the shaft key way?",
    immg: "img37",
    answer: "Feather key",
    options: [
      "Feather key",
      "Flat saddle key",
      "Circular taper key",
      "Hallow saddle key"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 38,
    question: "What is the purpose of normalising?",
    immg: "img38",
    answer: "To remove stress and strain",
    options: [
      "For adding cutting ability",
      "For developing high hardness",
      "To increase wear resistance",
      "To remove stress and strain"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 39,
    question: "What is the formula for circumference of a circle?",
    immg: "img39",
    answer: "2πr",
    options: ["πr", "πr²", "2πr", "πd"]
  },
  {
    numb: 40,
    question: "What is the formula for area of the circle?",
    immg: "img40",
    answer: "πr²",
    options: ["πd", "πr²", "2πr", "π/2r"]
  },
  {
    numb: 41,
    question: "Which line is called as chord?",
    immg: "img41",
    answer: "AB",
    options: ["ED", "AB", "OD", "OE"]
  },
  {
    numb: 42,
    question: "Which type of stress?",
    immg: "img42",
    answer: "Shear stress",
    options: [
      "Tensile stress",
      "Compressive stress",
      "Shear stress",
      "Torsional stress"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 43,
    question: "What is the unit of strain?",
    immg: "img43",
    answer: "No unit",
    options: ["Kg/cm2", "Newton/metre2", "Metre", "No unit"]
  },
  {
    numb: 44,
    question: "Which symbol is used to express change in length?",
    immg: "img44",
    answer: "δl",
    options: ["L", "δl", "I", "e"]
  },
  {
    numb: 45,
    question: "Riveted joints is a_______",
    immg: "img45",
    answer: "permanent joints",
    options: [
      "permanent joints",
      "temporary joints",
      "semi permanent",
      "none of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 46,
    question: "Identify the given rivet.",
    immg: "img46",
    answer: "Snap head",
    options: ["Snap head", "Flat head", "Counter sunk", "Pan head"]
  },
  {
    numb: 47,
    question: "Which materials pipe is used for drainage pipe line?",
    immg: "img47",
    answer: "PVC pipe",
    options: ["PVC pipe", "Brass Pipe", "G.I. Pipe", "Steel pipe"]
  },
  {
    numb: 48,
    question: "Which of the following is used to block the pipe at one end?",
    immg: "img48",
    answer: "Plug",
    options: ["Plug", "Union", "Reducer", "Couplings"]
  },
  {
    numb: 49,
    question: "Which one of the following accommodates four pipes in a pipe fitting?",
    immg: "img49",
    answer: "Cross",
    options: ["Union", "Cross", "Elbow", "Tee"]
  },
  {
    numb: 50,
    question: "The Included angle of pipe thread is around______",
    immg: "img50",
    answer: "55°",
    options: ["15°", "55°", "10°", "75°"]
  }
];


